Guide to the Hawthorne Family Papers, ca. 1800-1926
Department of Special Collections
- Series 6: Julian Hawthorne [1846-1934]: Correspondence and Miscellany
  - Correspondence, 1852-1926 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Item 19. To Clifford Smyth: TLS, 1925 Dec. 15., 1 leaf
    - Item 20. To Clifford Smyth: TLS, 1926 April 19., 1 leaf
    - Item 21. To Clifford Smyth: TLS, 1926 June 1., 1 leaf & cvr.
    - Item 22. To Clifford Smyth: TLS, 1926 June 26., 1 leaf
    - Item 23. To Clifford Smyth & Beatrix Hawthorne Smyth: TLS, 1926 Dec. 12., 1 leaf & cvr.
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Item 1. Being Alive: book prospectus, typescript, [n.d.]., 2 leaves.
    - Item 2. Printed fragment of newspaper editorial, [ca. 1912]
- Series 7: Anna Cora Mowatt [1819-1870]
  - Manuscript notes & verse, ca.1850s[?] (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Item 1. 54+ leaves; some print material.
- Series 8: Memorabilia
  - Memorabilia 1850s-1860s (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Item 1. H. Browne, An Illustration of Stonehenge and Abury.... Salisbury: Printed by J. Browne, n.d. Pamphlet, signed & dated: Nath Hawthorne[?] 16th 1856. Laid in: title page Hoyle s Card Games, Glasgow, 1827, signed: Nath: Hawthorne; signed in pencil: Julian Haw[illegible]1865 Concord [illegible]. In envelope marked in pencil: Clifford To keep for little Hawthorne [Smyth] From Marmie[?].
    - Item 2. Facsimile of Nathaniel Hawthornes hand, including signature, [n.d.]., 1 leaf. [Possibly an excerpt from a letter to Sophia A. Hawthorne.]
    - Item 3. Etching[?], [n.d.] On verso: Maria Louisa Hawt. Wrapper marked in Rose Hawthorne Lathrop s hand: memento of Aunt Louisa Hawthorne little picture owned by her.
    - Item 4. Envelope with 2 notes: a) Cards from Mr + Mrs Henry Bright Mr Henry Chorley Robert Browning; b) (Robert Browning card is not here 2/23/31) E.[T?].D.
    - Item 5. Envelope enclosing 2 calling cards: Mr. Henry A. Bright, Mrs. Henry A. Bright; not before 1860.
    - Item 6. Envelope addressed to Sophia A. Hawthorne in Boston; enclosed: calling card of Henry F. Chorley.
    - Item 7. Memorial card of Mrs. Blodget, 1862, in envelope addressed to Nathaniel Hawthorne.
    - Item 8. Photo of painting of Ruth.
- Series 9: Hawthorne Family Photographs
  - Sophia A. Hawthorne; Rose Hawthorne Lathrop (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Item 1. Envelope labeled in unknown hand [Rose Hawthorne Lathrops?]: Photograph of Mrs. Hawthorne in England, about 1859. [In 1998, this envelope enclosed the photograph of Sophia A. Hawthorne, below. This may be the photograph mentioned in Rose Hawthorne Lathrop s letter to Clifford Smyth, 1925 June 3.]
    - Item 2. Photograph: Sophia A. Hawthorne, [on verso, in Sophia A. Hawthornes hand: At Lisbon 1855].
    - Item 3. Photograph: Rose Hawthorne Lathrop, [ca. 1870?].
    - Item 4. Photograph: Rose Hawthorne Lathrop, [ca. 1870?].
    - Item 5. Photograph: Rose Hawthorne Lathrop, [ca. 1890?].
  - Daguerreotype, ca. 1855 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Una Hawthorne [1844-1877] & Julian Hawthorne